<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>
    <string name="app_name">Al-Mirats</string>
    <string name="txt_home">Home</string>
    <string name="txt_materi">Material</string>
    <string name="txt_feedback">Feedback</string>
    <string name="txt_fatwa">Fatwa</string>
    <string name="txt_welcome">Hello, Welcome to</string>
    <string name="txt_name">Al-Mirats</string>
    <string name="txt_desc_feedback">Provide your feedback and suggestions to improve your app experience. We appreciate your contributions to making the Heirs Calculator better!</string>
    <string name="txt_komentar">Enter your comments</string>
    <string name="txt_email">Enter your email</string>
    <string name="txt_materi_desc">Here, you will find some practical information about inheritance, related laws, and a guide to better understanding the process of dividing assets.</string>
    <string name="txt_card_desc_calculator">Easily fine-tune inheritance divisions with our accurate and user-friendly calculator feature.</string>
    <string name="txt_panduan">Guide</string>
    <!-- TODO: Remove or change this placeholder text -->
    <string name="hello_blank_fragment">Hello blank fragment</string>
    <string name="txt_tentang_aplikasi">About Application</string>
    <string name="txt_desc_app">The Al-Mirats Calculator is a mobile application resulting from a project produced in the Mobile Application Development Terk Course which was created according to the teachings of the Islamic religion. This application will make it easier for you to calculate inheritance distribution, in this application you can also learn about inheritance.</string>
    <string name="txt_nama_aplikasi">Application Name: Al-Mirats</string>
    <string name="txt_tim">Development Team:</string>
    <string name="txt_nama_pengembang">1. Arfan Prihardiasyah \n2. Bayu Mahesa \n3. Ryan Hidayat \n4. Haibraiel Rabbany F.Z \n5. Farhan Nur Fauziy \n6. Muhammad Rayhan Hakim</string>
    <string name="txt_dosen">Herika Hayurani, S.Kom., M.Kom</string>
    <string name="txt_dosen_pembimbing">Supervisor:</string>
    <string name="txt_klien">Client:</string>
    <string name="txt_nama_klien">Dr. H. Karimulloh, M.A</string>
    <string name="txt_sumber">Content Source:</string>
    <string name="txt_sumber_desc"><![CDATA[Kementrian Agama Republik Indonesia 2022. Al-Quran Digital. \nSupradiin.2020Fikih Mewaris & Hukum Kewarisan (Studi Analsisi Perbandingan)Sulawesi Selatan. Pustaka Almaida.]]></string>
    <string name="txt_kalkulator">Inheritance Calculator</string>
    <string name="txt_about">About</string>
    <string name="txt_materi_teratas">Top Material</string>
    <string name="txt_fitur_utama">Main Feature</string>
    <string name="txt_tutorial_desc">This tutorial guide will guide you step by step in understanding and utilizing the advanced features offered by Al Mirats.</string>
    <string name="txt_tutorial">Guide</string>
    <string name="txt_laki">Male</string>
    <string name="txt_perempuan">Female</string>
    <string name="txt_pilih_jenis_kelamin">Select the gender:</string>
    <string name="txt_informasi">Information</string>
    <string name="txt_materi_disarankan">Material Recommendation</string>
    <string name="txt_harta">Assets</string>
    <string name="txt_hutang">Debt</string>
    <string name="txt_jenazah">Perawat Jenazah</string>
    <string name="txt_gender">Gender</string>
    <string name="txt_total">Total Assets</string>
    <string name="txt_hint_harta">Enter the Heir\'s Assets</string>
    <string name="txt_hint_hutang">Enter Heir\'s Debt</string>
    <string name="txt_wasiat">Heir\'s Testament</string>
    <string name="txt_hint_wasiat">Enter the Testator\'s</string>
    <string name="txt_hint_jenazah">Enter Mortuary Care</string>
    <string name="txt_selanjutnya">Next</string>
    <string name="txt_ahli_waris">Heir</string>
    <string name="txt_bagian">Partition</string>
    <string name="txt_jumlah_orang">Number of people</string>
    <string name="txt_harta_bagian">Sectional Property</string>
    <string name="txt_harta_perorang">Individual Assets</string>
    <string name="txt_keterangan">information</string>
    <string name="txt_total_pembagian">Total Distribution of Assets</string>
    <string name="txt_jumlah">Total</string>
    <string name="txt_total_harta_bersih">Total Net Assets</string>

    <!--    TODO: MATERI-->
    <string name="title_materi_1">What is Inheritance</string>
    <string name="heading_materi_1">Definition and Terms in Inheritance Law</string>
    <string name="desc_materi_1">According to Indonesian legal expert, Prof.Dr. Wirjono Prodjodikoro (1976), inheritance law is defined as the law that regulates the position of a persons assets after he dies (heirs), and the ways in which these assets are transferred to other people (heirs). Meanwhile, based on Presidential Instruction Number 1 of 1991, the definition of inheritance law is the law that regulates the transfer of ownership rights to the heirs inheritance, then determines who has the right to be an heir and how much each share will be.</string>
    <string name="subheading_materi_1">The following are some terms in inheritance law:</string>
    <string name="subdesc_materi_1">1. An heir is a person who dies and leaves property to be distributed to those entitled to it (Heirs).\n
        \n2. Heirs are people who have the right to receive inheritance from the testator. There are heirs according to the provisions of the law called heirs under the general title (ab intestanto), there are heirs appointed by a will/testament called heirs under a special title (testamentary heirs).\n
        \n3. Inheritance is all the heirs inheritance in the form of rights and obligations or all the assets left by the person who died after deducting all his debts.\n
        \n4. A will is a decision made by a person (usually stated in a deed) which must be implemented after he dies. Wills due to unilateral actions can be revoked.\n
        \n5. Legitime portie is an absolute part, namely a part of the inheritance that cannot be reduced by testament or other gifts by the testator. The heirs who are entitled to this section are called "legitimate" namely straight-line heirs according to the law</string>

    <string name="title_materi_2">Verses Explaining About Inheritance</string>
    <string name="heading_materi_2">Verses from the Qur-an about Inheritance</string>
    <string name="desc_materi_2">There are several verses in the Qur-an that explain the distribution of inheritance. Among them is the word of Allah\n
         \nلِلرِّجَالِ نَصِيبٌ مِمَّا تَرَكَ الْوَالِدَانِ وَالْأَقْرَبُون َ وَلِلنِّسَاءِ نَصِيبٌ مِمَّا تَرَكَ الْوَالِدَانِ وَالْأَقْروبَُُ \n
         \nFor men there is the right to share in the assets inherited from their parents and relatives, and for women there is the right to share (also) in the assets inherited from their parents and relatives, whether a little or a lot according to the portion that has been determined. (QS. An Nisaa : 7)</string>
    <string name="subheading_materi_2">Reference</string>
    <string name="subdesc_materi_2">In the past, during the period of ignorance, the Arabs, due to their arbitrariness and harsh nature, did not give inheritance to weak people such as women and children, they only gave it to strong men. This is because, in their opinion, men are the ones who take part in war, and they are also the ones who have the right to receive the spoils of war. So Rabb, the Most Merciful, the Most Wise, wanted to establish a Shari ah that equalizes (the right to receive inheritance) between men and women, strong people and weak people. (Taisir Al-Karim Ar-Rahman fi Tafsir Kalam Al-Mannan, Page 201)</string>

    <string name="title_materi_3">Which Parties Have the Right to Receive Inheritance</string>
    <string name="heading_materi_3">the party entitled to receive it</string>
    <string name="desc_materi_3">The recipients of the inheritance are called heirs, and Islamic inheritance law has determined the order and portion of each heir. Heirs can consist of the nuclear family such as children, husband or wife, as well as wider family such as parents, siblings and even distant relatives.</string>
    <string name="subheading_materi_3">Reference</string>
    <string name="subdesc_materi_3">1. Al-Qur\'an, Surah An-Nisa (4:11-12)\n
        2. Hadis Riwayat Bukhari dan Muslim\n
        3. Hukum Waris Islam oleh Prof. Dr. Quraish Shihab\n
        4. Fatwa Majelis Ulama Indonesia (MUI) atau otoritas keagamaan setempat.\n</string>

    <string name="title_materi_4">What is the Structure of the Main Inheritance Division</string>
    <string name="heading_materi_4">Section for primary heirs</string>
    <string name="desc_materi_4">Primary heirs are individuals who hold the foremost entitlement to inherit an estate, commonly including spouses and children, although in certain legal frameworks, this designation may extend to encompass living parents or siblings. The distribution of assets within an estate entails dividing the deceased\'s property among primary heirs in accordance with applicable legal regulations. This distribution process may employ various methods, such as proportional allocation or assigning specific percentages to each heir. Testamentary inheritance introduces the possibility of a will dictating asset distribution in a manner distinct from standard inheritance laws, provided that the will adheres to relevant legal stipulations. Subsequently, managing and settling the estate typically entails tasks such as debt repayment, fulfillment of obligations, and overseeing estate administration following the allocation of assets among heirs.</string>
    <string name="subheading_materi_4"></string>
    <string name="subdesc_materi_4"></string>

    <string name="title_materi_5">Whose Parties are Blocked by the Main Heirs</string>
    <string name="heading_materi_5">Whose Party is Obstructed</string>
    <string name="desc_materi_5">In Islamic inheritance law, there is the concept of "main heir" who has a higher right to inherit than other heirs. The main heirs involve children, husband/wife, and parents. They have higher rights and get a fixed share of the inheritance. Other heirs, such as siblings, may be prevented from getting certain shares if the primary heir is still alive.
         For example, if there are surviving children, spouse, or parents, siblings may receive a smaller share or even be prevented from receiving an inheritance.</string>
    <string name="subheading_materi_5">Reference</string>
    <string name="subdesc_materi_5">A reference website that can provide further information regarding Islamic inheritance law is the Fatwa Institute of the Indonesian Ulema Council (MUI):
https://www.fatwamui.or.id/</string>

    <string name="title_materi_6">Definition of Aul and Radd in Waris</string>
    <string name="heading_materi_6">What is meant by Aul</string>
    <string name="desc_materi_6">Al-aul in Arabic has many meanings, including azh-zhulm (persecution) and unjust, as He said:\n\n That is closer to not committing wrongdoing. (an-Nisa: 3)\n\nAl-aul also means rising or overflowing. It is said alaa al-mau idzaa irtafaa which means the rising water is overflowing.\n\nAuls example is: \nThe portion of a husband who should get half ½ can change to a third ⅓ in certain circumstances, such as if the subject matter is increased from the original six 6 to nine 9. So in this case a husband who should get 3/6 and a half only gets 3/9 and a half</string>
    <string name="subheading_materi_6">What does Radd mean?</string>
    <string name="subdesc_materi_6">Ar-radd in Arabic means return/return or also means turn/turn away. As stated in the following words of Allah:\n\nMoses said: That is (the place) we are looking for. Then the two of them returned, following their original footsteps. \" (al-Kahf: 64)\n\nAnd Allah dispels those who disbelieve whose condition is full of irritation…\" (al-Ahzab: 25)\n\nIn a prayer it is said \"Allahumma radda kaidahum annii\" " (O Allah, turn away/banish their deceptions against me).\n\nAs for ar-radd according to the terms of faraid science scholars, it is a reduction in the subject matter and an increase/increase in the number of ashhabul furudh parts. Ar-radd is the opposite of al-aul.\nFor example, in a situation (in the distribution of inheritance rights) the ashhabul furudh have received their respective rights, but it turns out that the inheritance still remains - meanwhile there is no other relative figure as ashabah — then the remaining inheritance is given or returned to the ashhabul furudh according to their respective shares.</string>

    <!--    TODO: TUTORIAL-->

    <string name="desc_tutorial_1_1"></string>
    <string name="desc_tutorial_1_2"></string>
    <string name="desc_tutorial_1_3"></string>

    <string name="desc_tutorial_2_1">1. Fill your email first.</string>
    <string name="desc_tutorial_2_2">2. Fill in the comments you want.</string>
    <string name="desc_tutorial_2_3">3. Press the button to send your comment.</string>

    <string name="desc_tutorial_3_1">1. Press the following button to view the material in a list or grid.</string>
    <string name="desc_tutorial_3_2">2. Select an available material to view material details.</string>
    <string name="desc_tutorial_3_3"></string>

    <string name="desc_tutorial_4_1">1. You can see various kinds of information from this application.</string>
    <string name="desc_tutorial_4_2">2. This information includes the purpose of the application, as well as the development team, supervisors and reference sources for this application.</string>
    <string name="desc_tutorial_4_3"></string>

    <!--    TODO: FATWA-->
    <string name="title_fatwa_1">Haven\'t paid the fasting debt and then dies, will the heirs make up for it or what?</string>
    <string name="title_fatwa_2">Haven\'t performed aqiqah yet, is the aqiqah obtained from his father\'s inheritance or does the child perform aqiqah himself?</string>
    <string name="title_fatwa_3">Can male and female inheritance be equal?</string>
    <string name="title_fatwa_4">What if the inheritance is greater for those who have contributed more to the deceased?</string>
    <string name="title_fatwa_5">Is there a verse in the Koran that requires us to divide inheritance according to Sharia?</string>
    <string name="title_fatwa_6">What is the Law on Distributing Inheritance Not According to Allah SWT\'s Law?</string>
    <string name="title_fatwa_7">Wills for Heirs, Are They Required to Be Executed</string>

    <string name="desc_fatwa_1">In Islam, paying debts is an obligation that must be fulfilled. If someone dies before paying off the fasting debt, his heirs are responsible for making up for or paying the debt. Qadha is the replacement or implementation of something that is delayed. In this context, heirs can pay fasting debts that have not been completed by the deceased.</string>
    <string name="desc_fatwa_2">In Islam, diaqiqah is the slaughter of animals for newborn children. The law is the father\'s responsibility to carry out the diaqiqah of his inherited property. The father can perform the aqiqah for his child himself or ask someone else to do it on his behalf.</string>
    <string name="desc_fatwa_3">In Islam, the share of inheritance between men and women is not equal. Men\'s share of inheritance is greater than women\'s in some situations. In inheritance, a daughter gets half the inheritance of a son.</string>
    <string name="desc_fatwa_4">In Islam, the basic principle of dividing inheritance is fair and in accordance with the provisions stipulated in the Koran. Even though someone has contributed more to the deceased, the distribution of inheritance still follows the established provisions of Islamic inheritance law. It is not permitted to give a larger portion to one heir based solely on certain services.</string>
    <string name="desc_fatwa_5">In the Al-Qur\'an there are verses that regulate the distribution of inheritance according to sharia. One verse that explains this is in Surah An-Nisa (4:11-12):
         "11. Allah conveys His command to you regarding (distribution of inheritance) to your children: the share of one son is equal to the share of two daughters, and if there are more than two daughters, then they get two-thirds of the property who is left behind; and if she is only a daughter, then she will share half. And to the parents (heirs) of each of them one-sixth of the property he left behind, if he has children; and if he has no children and his parents inherit the property then his mother gets one-third. And if the one who leaves him has brothers or sisters, then each of them gets one-sixth. And if the person who leaves him has many brothers and sisters, then his sister gets one-sixth ; and to each of his brothers a portion. (That is) Allah's decree which He has given you; and Allah is All-Knowing, All-Wise."</string>
    <string name="desc_fatwa_6">Distributing inheritance not in accordance with Allah SWT\'s law (syar\'i) is considered a serious violation in Islam. Canceling or changing the inheritance provisions that have been determined by Islamic law can be considered an illegal action and can lead to sin. In Islam, observance of Allah\'s inheritance laws is an obligation, and violation of them can result in legal and moral consequences.</string>
    <string name="desc_fatwa_7">Wills in Islam are permitted, but there are certain limitations and conditions that must be followed. A will can only cover one third of the inheritance and must not harm the heirs determined by Islamic inheritance law. In this case, the will is not required to be fully implemented, but must comply with these provisions.</string>

    <string name="source_fatwa_1">1. Al-Qur\'an, Surah Al-Baqarah (2:180)\n2. Hadith History of Bukhari and Muslim\n3. Fatwa of the Indonesian Ulema Council (MUI) or local religious authority</string>
    <string name="source_fatwa_2">1. Hadith History of Ahmad and Abu Dawud\n2. Fatwa of the Indonesian Ulema Council (MUI) or local religious authority.</string>
    <string name="source_fatwa_3">1. Al–Qur\'an, Surah An–Nisa (4:11–12)\n2. Hadith History of Bukhari and Muslim\n3. Islamic Inheritance Law by Prof. Dr. Quraish Shihab</string>
    <string name="source_fatwa_4">1. Al-Qur\'an, Surah An-Nisa (4:7)\n2. Hadith History of Bukhari and Muslim\n3. Fatwa of the Indonesian Ulema Council (MUI) or local religious authority.</string>
    <string name="source_fatwa_5">Al–Qur\'an, Surah An–Nisa (4:11–12), Tafsir al-Jalalayn, Tafsir Ibn Kathir</string>
    <string name="source_fatwa_6">Al-Qur\'an, Surah An-Nisa (4:14): "And whoever breaks the agreement made with Allah after the agreement remains, and breaks what Allah has commanded to be connected, and create chaos on the face of the earth, then they are the ones who lose."</string>
    <string name="source_fatwa_7">Al–Qur\'an, Surah An–Nisa (4:11–12): "Allah conveys His command to you regarding (distribution of inheritance) your children: the share of a son equal to the share of two daughters, and if the daughters are more than two, then they get two-thirds of the property left behind; and if she is only a daughter, then she gets half."</string>
</resources>