<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>
    <string name="app_name">Al-Mirats</string>
    <string name="txt_home">Home</string>
    <string name="txt_materi">Material</string>
    <string name="txt_feedback">Feedback</string>
    <string name="txt_fatwa">Fatwa</string>
    <string name="txt_welcome">Hello, Welcome to</string>
    <string name="txt_name">Al-Mirats</string>
    <string name="txt_desc_feedback">Provide your feedback and suggestions to improve your app experience, We are thankful for your contribution toward making our Inheritance Calculator the best it can be!</string>
    <string name="txt_komentar">Enter your comments</string>
    <string name="txt_email">Enter your email</string>
    <string name="txt_materi_desc">Following are some practical details on inheritance and related laws and a guideline that helps you understand the process of dividing the assets better manner</string>
    <string name="txt_card_desc_calculator">Quickly calibrate the inheritance by distribution using our easy-to-use, accurate calculator feature.</string>
    <string name="txt_panduan">Guide</string>
    <!-- TODO: Remove or change this placeholder text -->
    <string name="hello_blank_fragment">Hello blank fragment</string>
    <string name="txt_tentang_aplikasi">About Application</string>
    <string name="txt_desc_app"> Al-Mirats Calculator is a Mobile Phone Application. This project was done during the Terk Course of Mobile Application Development and was developed according to the teachings of the Islamic religion. This application helps you to quickly calculate the distribution of inheritance. In this application, you can also learn about inheritance.</string>
    <string name="txt_nama_aplikasi">Application Name: Al-Mirats</string>
    <string name="txt_tim">Development Team:</string>
    <string name="txt_nama_pengembang">1. Arfan Prihardiasyah \n2. Bayu Mahesa \n3. Ryan Hidayat \n4. Haibraiel Rabbany F.Z \n5. Farhan Nur Fauziy \n6. Muhammad Rayhan Hakim</string>
    <string name="txt_dosen">Herika Hayurani, S.Kom., M.Kom</string>
    <string name="txt_dosen_pembimbing">Supervisor:</string>
    <string name="txt_klien">Client:</string>
    <string name="txt_nama_klien">Dr. H. Karimulloh, M.A</string>
    <string name="txt_sumber">Content Source:</string>
    <string name="txt_sumber_desc">Hassan Saleh. Kajian Fiqh Nabawi dan Fiqh Kontemporer. Jakarta: PT Raja Grafindo Persada, 2008;
        \n\nIrma Devita Purnamasari. Kiat-Kiat Cerdas, Mudah dan Bijak Memahami Masalah Hukum Waris. Bandung: Penerbit Kaifa, 2012;
        \n\nMaimun Nawawi. Pengantar Hukum Kewarisan Islam. Surabaya: Pustaka Radja, 2016;
        \n\nSajuti Thalib. Hukum Kewarisan Islam di Indonesia, Jakarta: PT. Bina Aksara, 1984;
        \n\nSudarsono. Hukum Perkawinan Nasional. Jakarta: Rineka Cipta, 2010.
        \n\nAbu Muslim. Faraidh: Ayat Al Qur’an Seputar Warisan, 2022.
        \n\nAhmad Azhar Basyir. Hukum Waris Islam. Yogyakarta: Penerbit Ekonisia, 2001.
        \n\nMohammad Daud Ali. 2004. Hukum Islam: Pengantar Ilmu Hukum dan Tata Hukum Islam di Indonesia, Edisi Keenam. Jakarta: PT. RajaGrafindo Persada.
        \n\nSayuti Thalib. 2016. Hukum Kewarisan Islam di Indonesia. Jakarta: Sinar Grafika.
        \n\nan-nur.ac.id. Pengertian Ashabah dan Pembagiannya, 2022.</string>
    <string name="txt_kalkulator">Inheritance Calculator</string>
    <string name="txt_about">About</string>
    <string name="txt_materi_teratas">Top Material</string>
    <string name="txt_fitur_utama">Main Feature</string>
    <string name="txt_tutorial_desc">This tutorial guide will guide you step by step in understanding and utilizing the advanced features offered by Al Mirats.</string>
    <string name="txt_tutorial">Guide</string>
    <string name="txt_laki">Male</string>
    <string name="txt_perempuan">Female</string>
    <string name="txt_pilih_jenis_kelamin">Select the gender:</string>
    <string name="txt_informasi">Information</string>
    <string name="txt_materi_disarankan">Material Recommendation</string>
    <string name="txt_harta">Assets</string>
    <string name="txt_hutang">Debt</string>
    <string name="txt_jenazah">Cadaver Costs</string>
    <string name="txt_gender">Gender</string>
    <string name="txt_total">Total Assets</string>
    <string name="txt_hint_harta">Enter the assets</string>
    <string name="txt_hint_hutang">Enter the debt</string>
    <string name="txt_wasiat">Testament (Maximum ⅓ Total Assets)</string>
    <string name="txt_hint_wasiat">Enter the testment</string>
    <string name="txt_hint_jenazah">Enter mortuary care</string>
    <string name="txt_selanjutnya">Next</string>
    <string name="txt_ahli_waris">Heir</string>
    <string name="txt_bagian">Partition</string>
    <string name="txt_jumlah_orang">Total</string>
    <string name="txt_harta_bagian">Sectional Property</string>
    <string name="txt_harta_perorang">Individual Assets</string>
    <string name="txt_keterangan">information</string>
    <string name="txt_total_pembagian">Total Assets</string>
    <string name="txt_jumlah">Total</string>
    <string name="txt_total_harta_bersih">Total Assets</string>
    <string name="txt_jumlah_istri">Number of Wifes</string>
    <string name="txt_jumlah_anak_laki_laki">Number of boys</string>
    <string name="txt_jumlah_anak_perempuan">Number of daughters (From boys)</string>
    <string name="txt_jumlah_cucu_laki_laki">Number of grandsons (From boys)</string>
    <string name="txt_jumlah_cucu_perempuan">Number of granddaughters</string>
    <string name="txt_pilih_anggota">Select existing family members</string>
    <string name="txt_pasangan">Does the testator have a partner?</string>
    <string name="txt_jumlah_saudara_seayah_seibu">Number of brother</string>
    <string name="txt_jumlah_saudari_seayah_seibu">Number of sister</string>
    <string name="txt_title">Enter the title</string>
    <string name="txt_ayah">Father</string>
    <string name="txt_ibu">Mother</string>
    <string name="txt_ayah_dari_ayah">Father\'s father (Grandmother)</string>
    <string name="txt_ibu_dari_ayah">Mother\'s father (Grandfather)</string>
    <string name="txt_ibu_dari_ibu">Mother\'s Mother (Grandmother)</string>
    <string name="txt_suami">Husband</string>
    <string name="txt_istri">Wife</string>
    <string name="txt_saudara_seayah_seibu">Brother</string>
    <string name="txt_saudari_seayah_seibu">Sister</string>
    <string name="txt_anak_laki">Son</string>
    <string name="txt_anak_perempuan">Daughter</string>
    <string name="txt_cucu_laki">Grand Son</string>
    <string name="txt_cucu_perempuan">Grand Daughter</string>
    <string name="txt_mail">*Send feedback via Gmail method.</string>
    <string name="source">Source</string>

    <!--    TODO: MATERI -->
    <string name="title_materi_1">What is Inheritance</string>
    <string name="heading_materi_1">Definition Inheritance</string>
    <string name="desc_materi_1">The word "inheritance" means the property or money left by the deceased. Inheritance will be constituted of many things, such as money, investments, or any other value. The contrasts that are here are between the words "inheritance" and the word "will." This means that inheritance is a property given by law, whether Islamic or civil. A will, on the other hand, is a document that explains the individual desires of the property owner and must be executed by the relevant law.
        \n\n The provisions related to inheritance under the principles of the Qur an, which are provided for in Islamic law, provide specific provisions. The laws would generally relate to the disposal of the assets upon the death of a person to their successors. In an Islamic inheritance, the system is based on considerations of justice. In Islamic law, the heirs are a husband, wife, children, parents, and siblings. The main aim of the Islamic inheritance system is that the family relationships and the level of dependence of the beneficiaries justify the level of inheritance assets received.</string>
    <string name="source_materi_1">https://www.prudentialsyariah.co.id/id/pulse/article/apa-itu-warisan/#:~:text=Pengertian%20Warisan,investasi%2C%20dan%20benda%20berharga%20lainnya.</string>

    <string name="title_materi_2">Verses Explaining About Inheritance</string>
    <string name="heading_materi_2">Verses from the Qur-an about Inheritance</string>
    <string name="desc_materi_2">There are several verses in the Qur-an that explain the distribution of inheritance. Among them is the word of Allah\n
         \nلِلرِّجَالِ نَصِيبٌ مِمَّا تَرَكَ الْوَالِدَانِ وَالْأَقْرَبُون َ وَلِلنِّسَاءِ نَصِيبٌ مِمَّا تَرَكَ الْوَالِدَانِ وَالْأَقْروبَُُ \n
         \nFor men there is the right to share in the assets inherited from their parents and relatives, and for women there is the right to share (also) in the assets inherited from their parents and relatives, whether a little or a lot according to the portion that has been determined. (QS. An Nisaa : 7)
         \n\n In the pre-Islamic period, the Arabs being unreasonable and rude in behavior used to inherit the stronger ones like men. The weak people, like women and children, remain ignorant just on behalf of being cowardly. According to their opinion, men are those who make war and peace, and besides, men only have the right to obtain the assets they get through their endless efforts. Thus, the Most Merciful, the All-wise, wanted a law that brings everybody on one level about men and women, strong people and weak people, a law initiated by Ar-Rabb. (Taisir Al-Karim Ar-Rahman fi Tafsir Kalam Al-Mannan, Page 201</string>
    <string name="source_materi_2">https://alukhuwah.com/2022/06/24/faraidh-ayat-al-quran-seputar-warisan/#:~:text=Dahulu%20bangsa%20Arab%20di%20masa,kepada%20laki%2Dlaki%20yang%20kuat.</string>

    <string name="title_materi_3">Which Parties Have the Right to Receive Inheritance</string>
    <string name="heading_materi_3">the party entitled to receive it</string>
    <string name="desc_materi_3">Those who receive the inheritance are called heirs, and Islamic inheritance law has determined the order and portion of each heir. Heirs can either consist of the nuclear family, such as children, husband, or wife, or even wider members of the family, like the parents, siblings, and even distant relatives.
        \n\nReference\n1. Al-Qur an, Surah An-Nisa (4:11-12)\n2. Hadith History of Bukhari and Muslim\n3. Islamic Inheritance Law by Prof. Dr. Quraish Shihab\n4. Fatwa of the Indonesian Ulema Council (MUI) or local religious authority.</string>
    <string name="source_materi_3"></string>

    <string name="title_materi_4">What is the Structure of the Main Inheritance Division</string>
    <string name="heading_materi_4">Section for primary heirs</string>
    <string name="desc_materi_4">A. Husband: He is due a part of the inheritance from the estate of the wife who has passed away if the wife has no children or any descendant from her children. The shares of the husband, in this case, are equal to a quarter of the wifes estate if she did not have children and an eighth if she has.\n
            \nB. Wife: If the husband has no children, the share of the inheritance that has to go to the wife is from the left-over part of the deceased husbands assets. In the absence of children, the wifes share is one-fourth of the husbands property; in the presence of children, the share is one-eighth.\n
            \nC. Children: The inheritance rights are excellent for children in Islam. For example, the boys get double the amount that the girls get. The amount that children get depends on the number of children that died and the number of sons and daughters surviving.\n
            \nD. Parents: The legal heirs also include parents whose portion would be determined depending on if their deceased child had children.\n
            \nE. Siblings: Both brothers and sisters, whether few or many in number, inherit a portion of the share of the property left by a brother or sister.</string>
    <string name="source_materi_4">https://www.hukumonline.com/klinik/a/cara-hitung-pembagian-harta-warisan-anak-menurut-hukum-islam-lt5b7021295093e/</string>

    <string name="title_materi_5">Whose Parties are Blocked by the Main Heirs</string>
    <string name="heading_materi_5">Whose Party is Obstructed</string>
    <string name="desc_materi_5">In Islam, there are some folks who cant inherit unless they are the absolute last ones left. These folks are called "mahrum." They cant get the main share of the inheritance if there are other relatives around. Here is why some people might be in this category:\n1. Not Muslim: If someone isnt Muslim, they usually cant inherit from a Muslim relative. This includes parents, siblings, or even kids who havent converted to Islam.\n\n2. Killer: If you kill someone who might inherit, you are automatically kicked out of the inheritance line. Theres a whole rule about it called "murder through inheritance rights." Basically, dont kill for money!\n\n3. This statement refers to a time in history when people were forced into servitude.  People who were enslaved had no control over their lives and couldnt build a future for themselves or their families.</string>
    <string name="source_materi_5">https://www.hukumonline.com/klinik/a/sebab-penghalang-waris-dalam-hukum-islam-lt50d46b1276aca/</string>

    <string name="title_materi_6">Understanding Aul and Radd in Waris</string>
    <string name="heading_materi_6">What is meant by Aul and Radd</string>
    <string name="desc_materi_6">Aul is a recalculation carried out to ensure that all heirs receive their fair share in accordance with Islamic law.\n\nAuls example is:\nThe share of a husband who should get half ½ can change to one third ⅓ in certain circumstances, such as if the subject matter is increased from the original six 6 to nine 9. So in this case a husband who should get 3/ 6 half only gets 3/9 one third.
    \n\nRadd, on the other hand, is the return of all or part of the inherited assets received by unrightful heirs.\n\nFor example, in a situation (in the distribution of inheritance rights) the heirs have received their respective rights, but it turns out that the inheritance still remains while there is no other relative as ashabah, then the remaining inheritance is given or returned again. to the ashhabul furudh according to their respective parts.</string>
    <string name="source_materi_6">https://www.hukumonline.com/klinik/a/pengaturan-iaul-i-dan-irad-i-dalam-kewarisan-islam-lt59658753e1272/</string>

    <string name="title_materi_7">Main Heir Section</string>
    <string name="heading_materi_7">Calculation of Main Heirs Share</string>
    <string name="desc_materi_7">1. If there is one daughter, she takes 1/2 share; if two or more than that jointly take 2/3 share, if the daughter is in addition to the son, then the sons share is double in proportion to one daughter.\n
        \n2. The father takes 1/3 share in case the heir leaves no children, but if children exist then, the father can take up to one-sixth of the share.\n
        \n3. Mother gets 1/6 share if she has children or two or more sisters or brothers. If she has no children or two or more sisters, you will get 1/3 of the share. After that, the mother gets 1/3 of what remains after the widow or widower takes together with the father.\n
        \n4. Share of the heir: 1/2 for the widower in the absence of children and 1/4 if there are children.\n
        \n5. Share of the heir is reduced to half if children remain and reduced to one-eighth if children are left.\n
        \n6. For a person dying and no children and fathers in that estate, then brothers and sisters get 1/6 each of the shares. And when two or more persons are found together, they shall receive 1/3 of the share.\n
        \n7. If a person dies leaving no children and father, and he has one biological sister or father, he will be given 1/2 share. It is that if the sister is with two or more biological or paternal sisters, then they both jointly get 2/3 share. If the sister is a partner with a biological brother or father, then the brothers share is two to one with the sister.</string>
    <string name="source_materi_7">https://www.hukumonline.com/klinik/a/cara-hitung-pembagian-harta-warisan-anak-menurut-hukum-islam-lt5b7021295093e/</string>

    <string name="title_materi_8">Definition of Ashobah, Mahjub, and Baitul Mal</string>
    <string name="heading_materi_8">Ashobah, Mahjub, and Baitul Mal</string>
    <string name="desc_materi_8">Ashabah in terms of terms means heirs who do not get a certain share but get the remaining part of the party who gets a certain share.\n\nA closely related heir is blocking Mahjub. Mahjub is entitled to inherit under the circumstances that there are no barriers. \n\nReligious Hall Treasures. If the heir leaves absolutely no heir or is not identifiable, then the assets, according to the discretion of the Religious Court, are transferred to Baitul Mal for the interest of Islamic religion and general welfare.</string>
    <string name="source_materi_8">https://an-nur.ac.id/ashabah-pengertian-dan-pembagiannya/\nhttps://eprints.walisongo.ac.id/id/eprint/6717/3/BAB%20II.pdf\n</string>

    <!--    TODO: TUTORIAL-->
    <string name="title_tutorial_1">Calculator Usage Guide</string>
    <string name="desc_tutorial_1">1. Fill in the heirs assets first\n2. Fill in the heirs debt\n3. Fill in the testators will\n4. Fill in the care costs for the corpse\n</string>

    <string name="title_tutorial_2">Guide to Using Feedback</string>
    <string name="desc_tutorial_2">1. Fill in the title first. \n2. Fill in the comments you want.\n3. Press the button to send your comment and select via Gmail.</string>

    <string name="title_tutorial_3">Guide on How to Read Material</string>
    <string name="desc_tutorial_3">1. Press the following button to view the material in a list or grid.\n2. Select an available material to view material details.</string>

    <string name="title_tutorial_4">Guide How to Read About the App</string>
    <string name="desc_tutorial_4">1. You can see various kinds of information from this application.\n2. This app lets you explore all sorts of details about it, like what it s for, who built it, and where they got their info.</string>

    <string name="title_tutorial_5">Guide on How to Read Fatwas</string>
    <string name="desc_tutorial_5">1. You can watch the fatwa video\n2. You can read the summary of the video</string>

    <!--    TODO: FATWA-->
    <string name="title_fatwa_1">Havent paid the fasting debt and then dies, will the heirs make up for it or what?</string>
    <string name="title_fatwa_2">Can male and female inheritance be equal?</string>
    <string name="title_fatwa_3">What if the inheritance is greater for those who have contributed more to the deceased?</string>
    <string name="title_fatwa_4">Is there a verse in the Koran that requires us to divide inheritance according to Sharia?</string>
    <string name="title_fatwa_5">What is the Law on Distributing Inheritance Not According to Allah SWT s Law?</string>
    <string name="title_fatwa_6">Wills for Heirs, Are They Required to Be Executed</string>

    <string name="desc_fatwa_1">Most Islamic scholars agree that their loved ones (heirs) shouldnt have to fast for them. Fasting is a very personal act of devotion, and it cannot be done by someone else after you re gone.
        \n\nSource: ChatGPT</string>
    <string name="desc_fatwa_2">Dividing inheritance in Islam can be complicated. Sometimes sons inherit more than daughters. Imagine a family inheritance as a pie. In certain situations, a son might get a bigger slice than a daughter. There are reasons behind this in Islamic law, but its important to remember that women can still inherit property and money in Islam.
        \n\nSource: ChatGPT</string>
    <string name="desc_fatwa_3">Dividing inheritance in Islam is meant to be fair, following guidelines laid out in the Quran. Even if someone took care of their loved one a lot, the inheritance gets split according to these established rules. You cannot give someone extra just because they helped out more.
        \n\nSource: ChatGPT</string>
    <string name="desc_fatwa_4">In the Al Qur an there are verses that regulate the distribution of inheritance according to sharia. One verse that explains this is in Surah An–Nisa (4:11–12):"11. Allah conveys His command to you regarding (distribution of inheritance) to your children: the share of one son is equal to the share of two daughters, and if there are more than two daughters, then they get two-thirds of the property who is left behind, and if she is only a daughter, then she will share half. And to the parents (heirs) of each of them one-sixth of the property he left behind, if he has children, and if he has no children and his parents inherit the property then his mother gets one-third. And if the one who leaves him has brothers or sisters, then each of them gets one-sixth. And if the person who leaves him has many brothers and sisters, then his sister gets one-sixth ; and to each of his brothers a portion. (That is) Allah s decree which He has given you; and Allah is All-Knowing, All-Wise."
        \n\nSource: ChatGPT</string>
    <string name="desc_fatwa_5">There are specific ways of dividing inheritance according to Allah s teachings in Islam. Going against those guidelines is quite a big deal; it is like changing the rules in the middle of the game. These inheritance laws are obligatory, and ignorance often causes problems on this planet and in the world hereafter.
        \n\nSource: ChatGPT</string>
    <string name="desc_fatwa_6">In Islam, you can definitely make a will, but there are some ground rules. You can only give away a third of your stuff, and it cannot mess with who gets what according to Islamic inheritance law. Basically, your will cannot leave your loved ones (heirs) out in the cold.
        \n\nSource: ChatGPT</string>
    <string name="txt_copyright">Copyright © by Rumah Fiqih Indonesia</string>

</resources>